let's plot the function f of x equals
sine of X on this axis below
we notice that if we plot a point on
this curve we can draw the linear
approximation or the tangent line to the
curve and we can compute the slope of
this tangent line
we can then move the point along the
curve and we note that the slope of the
corresponding tangent line changes as we
move the point we can see that the slope
of the tangent line ranges between
negative one and one in this picture
so let's take this one step further and
let's plot the slopes of the tangent
lines on a separate axis system as we
move the point along the curve f of x
equals sine X we map out the slopes of
the tangent lines on the second axis
below
it turns out and you can see it visually
that the slope function of f of x equals
sine X is the function f Prime of x
equals cosine X to prove this requires
more work but this is a nice visual
representation of the fact that the
derivative of sine is cosine